man! I really need a summer internship so
I can graduate on time
I remember hearing in my co-op prep
course then you just send 100 emails
just to get ten interviews
I've been
using this browser extension called Pen pal
it's really helped me with
generating emails for a bunch of job interviews I've had to do
you should check it
out and see how it works
yes, that sounds good.
I'm gonna show you a
couple of great features of pen pal
one is that you can upload your resume once and
have it save it so that you can use it multiple times
so you can go to my
account, my resume,  and then you can upload a resume so you would browse and upload
it
and then you can say upload and it'll be saved so that you can use it when
you're composing emails
another similar feature is you can save your skills so that you don't have to continue typing them over and over again
so you would go
to the edit profile page and in there
you could edit your skills and then hit
the Save button and it'll take you back
to my account
another great feature is
when you go to compose your emails so
I'll hit the compose email button and so
here are the list of different templates
that are saved and you can also save
custom templates.
in this case I'm a student and I'm trying to write a job inquiry email so I'll click on that
template and it'll show you a preview of
the email and you'll hit next button and
then you can fill out the fields so the
skills will automatically be populated
with that you saved and then you can edit
the following fields so this would be
the employer name I mean the employer
email the employer name and the company
name so you can fill those out and then
you hit the next button and it'll
automatically generate an email for you
and it'll address it to the right person
from
the email that you've provided and it'll
fill out just a general template
including your skills and the company
that you want to work for and then when
you hit the next button it provides a
built-in error checker so this is saying
to select the texts highlighted because
it detected an error so you can click on
that and you can say okay so it wants to
say I am instead of I'm so you can hit
apply correction and it'll change it for
you and then after that you can hit the
attach resume so that your resume will
automatically be sent as an attachment
to the email and then you can hit the
send button and it's sent so that would
be one email and then you could go back
and do similar thing and all you would
have to do is edit the employer fields
to the next employer that you would send
it to and can write a lot of emails efficiently
PenPal, the future of emails.
Penpal's an extension for your browser that
allows you to compose emails with ease.
There's a grammar and spellcheck tool to
eliminate easy to miss errors when
responding to employers
it also has a template function that
students may easily send hundreds of
emails when looking for an interview to
go on co-op..
[music]